Nico Sherban

TEACHER | B.SC. IN GEOPHYSICS

About Me

During the past several years, I developed many caring, leadership, and professional skills while often experiencing life outside of my comfort zone. I have lived in six and traveled through more than 25 countries. Along this journey, I became an experienced international teacher with high-level technical and analytical skills enriched through the Geophysics degree I obtained at the University of Calgary in Canada. I enjoy the heterogeneity and richness our world offers to us. I am nourished by this interest and have gained a profound cultural awareness let me to better understand and communicate with people from many nations. I highly value diverse experiences, opinions, and world views that others have to offer, and try to apply what I have seen and learnt from others to improve myself and contribute to the world around me.



Education

UNIVERSITY OF CALGARY

SEP 2011 - MAY 2015

Bachelor of Science in Geophysics

Relevant courses:

- Time series analysis and 1D data (A)
- Advanced structural geology. (A)
- Multidimensional data analysis (A-)
- Geophysical Interpretation (A-)
- Physical Properties of Rocks (A)
- Seismic theory (B+)
- Field school (Data acquisition using seismic, GPS, electrical resistivity tomography, and gravity methods .) (C+)
- Multivariate Calculus (B-)

Experience

IDIOMO CANADA JUL 2022 - PRESENT

English Teacher

Main responsibilities:

- Facilitate English discussions about a variety of topics with upper-intermediate and advanced adult students.
- Teach Canadian pronunciation, idioms and communicative culture.
- Use Zoom and its features to deliver high-quality classes.

SUNSHINE VILLAGE ACADEMY

NOV 2021 - PRESENT

Elementary Teacher

Main responsibilities:

- Prepare well-structured, diversified lessons in alignment with The Ivy Global syllabus.
- Teach a variety of subjects including language arts, math, science and social studies.
- Teach small groups and individual students online using Google Meets.
- Evaluate assignments and assessments.
- Meet with parents to discuss students' progress.
- Write student reports after every lesson detailing their participation, understanding and progress.
- Maintain student attendance records, grades and other required records.
- Collaborate with faculty and administration to evaluate and improve learning outcomes.
- Support and contribute to the development of individual education plans.
- Encourage student progress and engagement by truly learning spaces.
- Differentiate teaching methods and material for a diverse range of learning styles and skill



- m April 7, 1993
- Male
- 14039781667
- jnsherban7@gmail.com
- Calgary, Alberta
- i www.linkedin.com/in/nico-she

SKILLS -

Problem solving

Public Speaking

Logical thinking and creativity

Microsoft Office & Google Workspace

HTML, CSS

JavaScript, Python

English

Spanish

Portuguese

INTERESTS -

- Geography
- Travel
- Web Development
- Languages

levels.

ILA VIETNAM AUG 2017 - OCT 2021

ESL Teacher

Main responsibilities:

- Design fun, creative lessons in accordance with the Cambridge curriculum.
- Teach a wide range of ages and levels from three years old to adult, and beginner to advanced.
- Administer, grade and give feedback on tests, including IELTS prep speaking and writing tests.
- Participate in student recruitment, registration and placement activities.
- Participate in professional development workshops.
- Teach online when needed with Zoom and Google Meets.
- Use differential teaching methods for a range of learning styles.
- Supervise classroom behavior and moderate discussions to maintain a respectful environment.
- Maintain student attendance records, grades and other required records.
- Participate in campus and community events.

Certifications

In progress: The Complete JavaScript Course 2022: Zero to Mastery 2022 on Udemy.

In progress: The Complete Web Developer: Zero to Mastery on Udemy. 2022 Includes: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Github, Bootstrap, API's, Databases and more.

IV Certificate in TESOL certified by the Australia International College 2017 of Language.

2015-2021 Previously a Member-in-training with APEGA & eligible to be a professional APEGA member.

Honors & Awards

Jason Lang scholarship for outstanding academic achievement.

2014

Photography

Fitness